Nicholas Malzacher

WEB DEVELOPER

About Me

GitHub Portfolio: https://malzacher.github.io/react-portfolio/

I'm a passionate web developer and SEO specialist with experience crafting diverse websites and applications. From Shopify and WordPress to custom React and PHP projects, I bring creativity and technical expertise to every project. I thrive on building userfriendly, optimised solutions that not only look great but also perform exceptionally in driving results.

Academic Qualifications

RMIT University Bachelor of Information Technology, set to graduate in Semester 1 2023.

2018 - 2022

2008 - 2018

2022

2024

Wesley College Melbourne Campus (VCE)

In 2018 I successfully completed year 12 certificate, my subjects included English, Biology, Geography, Further Mathematics & Business Management.

Additional Academic Qualifications

Udemy Full Stack Development Course

I completed a Udemy course that teaches the ins and outs of full stack development and have learnt a great deal regarding HTML, CSS, and JavaScript as of current.

Udemy React (Next.js) Course

I am currently completing the 'React - The Complete Guide 2024 (including Next.js and Redux).' This course covers everything related to React and its best practices.

Experience

EXPERIENCE WITH

Vanilla Javascript Next.is

React (JSX) Shopify

JavaScript WooCommerce PHP

AWARDS & ACHIEVEMENTS

- Coco Ruby Plastic Surgery APAC (Asia Pacific) Search Award 2024 - 'Best Use of Search - Health'
- Wilson Parking Global Search Awards 2023 -'Best Local Campaign (SEO): Small'

Wordpress

- Essential Coffee APAC (Asia Pacific) Search Award 2023 - 'BEST USE OF SEARCH - B2B'
- UniSQ (University of South Queensland) -Semrush Search Awards 2023 (AU) - 'Highest Website Visitor Growth'

PERSONAL SKILLS

Communication skills, Problem-solving skills, Adaptability, Attention to detail, Time management skills, Teamwork, Creativity, Working in fast paced environments

ACHIEVEMENTS

3.0 GPA (Distinction Average) (University)

HOBBIES AND INTERESTS

I am passionate about web-design, fashion, gaming, the gym and spending time with both friends & family.

REFERENCES

Available on request.

CONTACT DETAILS

Nicholas Malzacher Phone: 0490 134 966

Email: Nicholas.malzacher@gmail.com

Work History

Clearwater Agency MAR 2023 – CURRENT

Web Developer & Seo Specialist

I am an experienced SEO specialist and web developer with 2 years at Clearwater Agency, where I manage around 30 high-impact campaigns for a diverse range of clients, including large-scale brands. In a fast-paced environment, I have consistently delivered outstanding results, earning four SEO and web awards for my campaigns. My expertise spans a variety of platforms and frameworks, including Next.js, React, Shopify, WordPress, headless WooCommerce, and more. I thrive on challenges and am passionate about driving measurable growth through innovative digital strategies.

The Albion Rooftop Bar

DEC 2021 - MAR 2023

Bartender

My Responsibilities at The Albion currently include point of sales operation, cash handling, guest service, beverage serving and general bartending responsibilities

Movo Kitchen JAN 2015 - FEB 2022

Web Developer

While working at Movo Kitchen, I developed and managed the restaurant's custom WordPress website, utilizing PHP and Advanced Custom Fields (ACF). In addition to my web development responsibilities, I simultaneously worked as front-of-house staff.

Sandbar beach Café and Bar

OCT 2020 - MAR 2021

Retail / Food and Beverage handling

My responsivities while working at sandbar was general café work such as working a till, food and beverage waiting and general cocktail making.

APS Group SEP 2019 - MAR 2020

Recruitment Consultant

In this position I worked doing rostering, shift rescheduling, termination, email updates and other general admin tasks.

GitHub Portfolio: https://malzacher.github.io/react-portfolio/ **LinkedIn:** https://www.linkedin.com/in/nicholas-malzacher/

Email: Nicholas.Malzacher@gmail.com